MATHEW COWDERY Software Developer

Dayton OH | 724.888.4077 | mcowdery@gmail.com | linkedIn.com/in/mathewcowdery| github.com/mcowdery

SUMMARY

Veteran with 5+ years of experience as a Cryptologic Analyst working with the Department of Defense (US Navy), 1+ year as a Software Developer, and 15+ years of overall professional experience.

Has a diverse background in the areas of business, software development, and cryptologic intelligence.

Demonstrates adaptability, leadership, professional demeanor, good interpersonal skills, and ability to excel in a high-paced environment.

TECHNICAL AND TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

Computational Thinking Fundamentals ● Back-end Computer Programming/Object-Oriented Programming ● Front-end Web Development ● C# ● .NET ● REST API ● TDD ● Spring Boot ● Spring MVC ● JPA ● Scrum ● HTML ● CSS ● JavaScript ● Git ● React

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECT EXPERIENCE We Can Code IT

Planned, designed, and Interactive applications in collaborative, team-based, and independent settings demonstrating the proficiency to earn Software Development Certificate.

Project Name

- Technologies used: Python, React.js, Redux, Node.js, PostgreSQL
- Designed and implemented a movie recommendation application in a 4-person team over 10 weeks.
- Enabled users to be recommended to movies based on 50+ data points; awarded most innovative project by (instructors).

Project Name

- Technologies used: Python, React.js, Redux, Node.js, PostgreSQL
- Designed and implemented a movie recommendation application in a 4-person team over 10 weeks.
- Enabled users to be recommended to movies based on 50+ data points; awarded most innovative project by (instructors).

Project Name

- Technologies used: Python, React.is, Redux, Node.is, PostgreSQL
- Designed and implemented a movie recommendation application in a 4-person team over 10 weeks.
- Enabled users to be recommended to movies based on 50+ data points; awarded most innovative project by (instructors).

EDUCATION

We Can Code IT, Columbus, OH 2023

Certificate of Software Development

Geneva College, Beaver Falls, PA 2010 - 2013

B. S. Computer Science

WORK EXPERIENCE

Entrepreneur (Self-employed)
Airbnb Business Owner & Host, Dayton OH

August 2022-Present

GitHub: https://yourname.github.io

2023

• Received business development and entrepreneurship experience while starting and managing a successful Airbnb business. Hosted over 240+ guests with an average review score of 4.98 out of 5 stars. (https://www.airbnb.ca/users/show/393992041)

Booz Allen Hamilton

Software Developer/Cryptologic Analyst, Ft. Meade, MD

August 2021-August 2022

• Worked and trained on various classified projects. Unclassified tools used included Python, Git, GitLab, Docker, AWS, and Jupyter Notebook.

U.S. Navy,

CTR2 (E-5), Wahiawa, HI

May 2016–May 2020

- Lead Proforma Analyst (August 2017—May 2020): Provided crucial situational awareness and Indications and Warnings to forward-deployed naval forces in the PACOM Area of Responsibility (AOR), preparing and disseminating over 3,000 high priority PROFORMA products to combatant commanders across the AOR.
- Area Analyst (March 2019—May 2020): Constructed and delivered 18 daily intelligence briefs to senior leadership with CTF 1070. Responsible for editing and releasing 21 theater assessments to provide situational awareness and posturing of AOR to 3rd, 5th, and 7th fleets, Pacific Command, deployed to US assets, and FVEY partners.
- Chief of Naval Operations Special Missions Operator (September 2017–May 2020): Drafted and released 585 time-critical reports, and reviewed over 660 messages in support of Special Access CNO Directed missions. Improving situational awareness to Pacific Fleet combatants with threat warning and actionable intelligence, resulting in successful operation with zero incidents reported for the program.
- **Department Training Petty Officer** (August 2017–February2020): Responsible for tracking and managing over 250 Sailor's General Military Trainings (GMT's), leading to 100% accountability for all personnel

Securitas Security Services,

Security Officer, Pittsburgh, PA

June 2008-May 2016

• Supervised site personnel as site supervisor. Managed over a dozen personnel, ensuring 100% manning of all posts.